<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Coderade blog</title>
    <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Coderade blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 21:44:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://coderade.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Hoisting with var, const and let in ES6, When I can use them?</title>
      <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/es6/const-and-let/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 21:44:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coderade.github.io/post/es6/const-and-let/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the most recognizable addition to the JavaScript language was that of const and let. Two new key words that allow us to declare variables, which behave differently than var.
When choosing which JavaScript variable to use, there are a number of factors we have to weigh. We have var, const, and let available to us, and we need to think what is the scope of each of these variables?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ES5, ES6, ES7 and ES2015 and ES2016. Isn&#39;t it just all JS?</title>
      <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/js-es6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 21:44:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coderade.github.io/post/js-es6/</guid>
      <description>JS, Why we love you? One of my biggest loves on the coding word is the JS (JavaScript) language.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but since I started to make simple code with JQuery and to research about the language under your hood and I got what is JS, the first thing that I did was thanked how the coding world can be really beautiful and simple with a programming language like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails 5 new features</title>
      <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/rails-5-new-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coderade.github.io/post/rails-5-new-features/</guid>
      <description>On this post I will try to show the new features, improvements and other important changes to Ruby on Rails version 5.
I will try to show how to use the most important features of Rails 5, including Action Cable, Action Controller Renderer, Turbolinks, the Active records, Attributes API and how to use Rails exclusively as a JSON API.
Besides that I will discuss the many other smaller changes in improvements such as the Rails command Router, new Date and Time methods, Secure Tokens and changes to parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi there!</title>
      <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coderade.github.io/post/first/</guid>
      <description>Hi there.
After a few attempts with the coderade .in and .io blogs, I started to write in a blog again and now with no expensive domain and freedom in customization excuses, heheh.
On this blog I will write about code, life hacks and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share my experiences in this vast life (yeah, with 23 years old).
The blog is powered by Hugo and I normally use the IDEA to write my posts with Markdown ❤️.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>