<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Coderade blog</title>
    <link>https://coderade.github.io/categories/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Coderade blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 13:47:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://coderade.github.io/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspect APK files with the APK Analyzer on Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/android/inspecting-apk-files-after-packaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coderade.github.io/post/android/inspecting-apk-files-after-packaging/</guid>
      <description>The Android Studio 2.2 added a new tool called the APK Analyzer.
It lets you look at packaged apps, those APK files that are in zip archive format that you use to deploy an application.
Using the APK Analyzer, you can see inside the APK file and see what files and directories are largest so you can decide how you can shrink down that APK.
The example application I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use the Apk Analyzer tool with an existing project that is available on my GitHub, where you can clone or download and try to follow the below steps on your own Android Studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Studio and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://coderade.github.io/post/android/android-studio-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coderade.github.io/post/android/android-studio-idea/</guid>
      <description>I personally love the JetBrains tools.
When I started to code with the Eclipse, Netbeans, ADT tool (For android development on Eclipse), Text editors and others tools, I thought to myself:
 &amp;ldquo;The development with these tools is pretty cool, but the tolls are very far from being awesome, can they be better?&amp;rdquo;
 So, after some time with a hard time with these tools I had the opportunity to try Intellij Idea working with Java development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>